马吃掉后的象
Knight to queen's bishop-five.
高招  莱纳德要如何应对
Oh, very nice. what's leonard going to do this?
是舍弃卒  还是改换布局呢
Does he give up the pawn or does he give up the position?
马上揭晓
Let's find out.
莱纳德  准备好了吗
Leonard, ready?
-好了  -开始
- Ready.  - Go.
该死  滑了一下
Damn it. I slipped.
真可惜
Too bad.
但你清楚激光障碍特工象棋的规则
you know the rules of secret agent laser obstacle chess.
莱纳德又死了  谢尔顿  你上吧
Leonard died again, sheldon. you're up.
虽然我深爱象棋  激光和空气消毒剂
Despite my deep love of chess, lasers and aerosol disinfectant,
但我必须放弃
I must forfeit.
为什么
Why?
-因为快到11点了  -那又怎样
- Because it's almost 11:00. - so?
佩妮给我立了"11点前敲门就往喉咙揍一拳"规则
So, penny has a "don't knock or I punch you in the throat" rule.
这个主意好不好
Hey, you know what'd be a great idea?
我们找些女生来玩激光视觉脱衣象棋
We get some girls over here and play laser optical strip chess.
相信我  霍华德  肯玩象棋的女生
Believe me, howard, any girl who would be willing to play that,
你不会想看她们的裸体
You don't want to see naked.
你太低估我了
You underestimate me.
佩妮  佩妮
Penny. penny.
佩妮
Penny.
好啊  谢尔顿
Hey, sheldon.
上午11点到了
It's 11:00 a.m.
我知道  你安全了
I know. you're safe.
包裹送到时  你在上班
This package came while you were at work
太好了  我订的莱茵石  谢谢
oh, great, my rhinestones.Thank you.
-等等  -怎么了
- Excuse me. - what?
你要签收
You have to sign this.
这是什么
What is it?
我签收了包裹
When I signed for the package,
我就代表邮递公司
I was deputized by the united parcel service
并受委托最终送达
And entrusted with its final delivery.
我现在要你确认收到包裹
I now need you to acknowledge receipt of the package
我才算完整履行法律义务
So that i'm fully indemnified and no longer liable.
谢尔顿  只不过是一盒莱茵石而已
Sheldon, it's just a box of rhinestones.
这跟物品无关
Well, the contents are irrelevant.
法定委托关系已经形成
A legal bailment has been created.
你一点都不重视吗
Is that mean nothing to you?
没有人会重视这个
It means nothing to anybody.
过来  给你看看我做的东西
Come here, let me show you what I'm doing.
‘委托’在普通法里的解释是
"bailment" describes a relationship in common law
当个人的私有财产
where a physical possession of personal property,
或者说动产
or "chattels,"
从委托人一方转移到
is transferred from one person, the bailor,
受托人一方
To another person, the bailee...
对对对  快看
Yeah, yeah, yeah. look, look, look!
我做起了一门生意
I started a business.
显然不是干净的生意
Obviously, not a cleaning business.
不是  我在做花花发夹  看
No, I'm making flower barrettes. see?
我起了个名字叫佩妮花花
I call them penny blossoms.
我给自己做了一个
I made one for myself,
接着店里的女生也想要
then all the girls at work wanted one.
然后我拿给在旧城镇开店的老板娘看
Then I showed some to this lady who runs a shop in old town.
她卖一些卡和自制首饰
She sells cards and homemade jewels,
她说想卖呢  我答应了
She said she wanted to sell them. I said, "okay."
一周里我赚了156美刀
And in one week,i made a $156.
真好  签收吧
Good for you, Sign here.
谢尔顿  你没听懂吗
Sheldon, don't you get it?
如果生意做下去
If this takes off,
我就不用当服务员了
I won't have to be a waitss anymore.
那周二晚上谁给我带干酪汉堡
But then who will bring me my cheeseburger on tuesday nights?
其他服务员呗
Another waitress.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
我怎么知道
I don't know.
那你还放心让她负责我的食物
And you're going to let her handle my food?
南希  她叫南希
Nancy. her name is nancy.
你瞎编的名字吧
I think you're just making that up.
谢尔顿  抱歉不能给你带牛肉汉堡了
Sheldon, I'm sorry about your hamburger, okay?
我不想一辈子就做个服务员
I just don't want to be a waitress for the rest of my life.
干酪汉堡  我要的是干酪汉堡
Cheeseburger. I get a cheeseburger.
行  干酪汉堡
Fine, cheeseburger.
说不定让南希负责更好
Maybe I'd be better off with nancy.
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
这门生意能做  对吧
I mean, this could be a business, right?
你一天能做几个
How many of these can you make a day?
大概20个
About 20.
每个...佩妮花花能赚多少
And how much profit do you make per...Penny blossom?
不知道  50美分吧  不确定
I don't know, like, 50 cents. I'm not sure.
你当然确定不了  好吧
Of course you're not. all right...
1天10美刀乘以1周5天
Ten dollars a day times five days a week
乘以1年52周等于2600美刀
Times 52 weeks a year is $2,600.
就这么多
That's all?
只是税前
Before taxes.
我又不用为这些交税
I don't have to pay taxes on this stuff.
我相信国税局会强烈反对
I believe the internal revenue service would strongly disagree.
但是  如果你利用现代营销技巧
But, if you took advantage of modern marketing techniques,
优化生产过程
And you optimized your manufacturing process,
或者能做好这门生意
You might be able to make this a viable business.
你知道怎么做吗
And you know about that stuff?
佩妮
Penny...
我可是物理学家
I'm a physicist.
拥有整个宇宙
I have a working knowlge of the
及其所有事物的相关知识
Entire universe and everything it contains.
电台司令[乐队名]是谁
Who's radiohead?
囧囧囧囧囧
我有宇宙重要事物的相关知识
I have a working knowledge of the important things in the universe.
祝你好运
Good luck.
谢尔顿  等等
Sheldon, hold on.
你能教我怎样才能赚多点钱吗
Could you maybe show me how to make more money with this.
我当然有能力教你
Of course I could
谢尔顿  等等
Sheldon, wait!
你会教我吗
Will you?
首先声明  你要我协助你
Just to be clear here, you're asking for my assistance.
是的
Yes.
你要明白  这牵扯到给你解释怎么做
And you understand that will involve me telling you what to do?
我明白
I understand.
而你不准对我明嘲暗讽
And you're not allowed to be sarcastic or snide to me while I'm doing so.
好吧
Okay.
很好
Good.
我们的首要前提是
Let's begin with the premise that
你之前所做的全都不对
Everything you've done up to this point is wrong.
哇哦  我也猜到了
Oh, Imagine that.
-讽刺我  拜拜  -不是  对不起  回来
Sarcasm. good-bye. No, sorry, wait. Please come back.
《生活大爆炸》
第二季  第18集
完工
There. done.
好
All right.
-用了12分17秒  -噢!
12 minutes and 17 seconds. oh!
还不错吧?
Pretty good, right?
计算佩妮花花一小时的产量
Penny ossoms per hour.
再算上批量购买的材料费用
Based on your wholesale selling price,
你一天实际上只能赚...
You'll effectively be paying yourself...
5.19美元
$5.19 a day.
一天?
"a day"?
连印度尼西亚的球鞋场童工都赚得比你多
There are children in a sneaker factory in indonia who outearn you.
这不可能
That just can't be right.
-你质疑我的数学能力?  -不  抱歉
You're questioning my math? no, sorry.
想见识下我的数学大作吗?
Want me to show my work?
天啊  千万别
Oh, god, no.
告诉我该怎么做就好
Just please tell me what to do about it.
好吧
All right.
你知道奥诺雷·布兰在1778年开发的
Are you familiar with the development
可互换零件吗 ?
in 1778 used interchangeable parts?
好吧  就是生产流水线
The assembly line, of course.
听着  既然我不讥讽你
Okay, you know what, if I'm not allowed to be snide,
你也不准显摆
You're not allowed to be condescending.
原始协议内不包含这条
Sthat wasn't a part of our original agreement,
所以我不同意
And I don't agree to it now.
好吧  算了
L right, fine.
我们怎么在公寓里架机器和传送带?
How are we supposed to set up machines and conveyor belts in my apartment?
你那是指流动生产线
You're thinking of the moving assembly line,
可以理解  但依然错得不可原谅
An understandable but not excusable mistake. no.
流动生产线是在1908年由亨利·福特发明的
The moving assembly line, that was introduced by henry ford in 1908.
这项创新通过低成本的生产商品
That innovation is what made possible our modern consumer
造就了现代消费文化
Culture by enabling a low-unit cost for manufactured goods.
你说的那个电台司令肯定不知道这个东西吧
I guess that isn' one of the topics discussed on your radiohead.
来吧  可别错过好戏
Let's go. we're going to miss the coming attractions.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
我在吃掉最后一个卒时扭伤了我的蛋蛋
I think I bruised a testicle capturing that last pawn.
请稍等片刻  我便将他放倒!
* Give me some timeon ato blow the man down *
我是香港的深海水兵  初来乍到
* I'm a deepwatesailor just come fromong Kong *
让开让开  我来把他放倒
* Give me way, hey, blow the man down *
给我些威士忌
* If you give me some whiskey *
听我把歌儿为你唱
* I'll sing you a song *
请稍等片刻  我便将他放倒!
* Give me some time to blow the man down. *
喂
Hello?
-好啊  -好啊
Hello. Hello.
船尾甲板上的同胞
* Come quickly lay aft
离开岗哨  快快来吧
* To the break of the poop *
帮我把他放倒!
* To me way, hey, blow the man down *
不然我会用靴子将你踢倒
* Or I'll help you along with the toe of my boot *
请稍等片刻  我便将他放倒!
* Give me some me to blow the man down.
等下  怎么回事?
W-W-Wait, what's going on?
你是指水手之歌吗?
I assume you're referring to the sea chanty.
这是一首很有节奏的工作歌
It's a rhythmic work song
能够提高产量
designedo increase productivity.
没错  虽然很疯狂  但的确很有效
Yeah, it's crazy, but it totally works.
看吧  我们不用3分钟
Look, we made is Penny Blossom
就完成了一个佩妮花花
in under three minutes.
很赞  但似乎我更加一头雾水了
Terrific, but that kind of raises more questions than it answers.
佩妮在做头饰
Penny's making hair accessories.
我的工作是最优化生产过程
I'm helping her optimize her manufacturing process.
好了  休息时间结束
Alright, break's over.
听好命令  你们全体为一...
* Pay attention to orders now you one and all... *
等等  你用的什么黏合剂?
Hold on. What are you using as a bonding agent?
热熔胶
Hot glue.
不会吧
You're kidding.
任何快干胶都比它好
Any of the cnoacrylates would do a better job.
不管用  这花容易渗水
It won't work, the flower'too porous.
我们把矽胶原液注进底层
What if we infused the bottom layer
这样就有了一个更牢固的底座
with silicone-RTV to provide a better mounting surface?
好主意
Intriguing.
问得好
Good question.
你有什么市场营销渠道吗?
Wh are your marketing and distribution channels?
呃  和我一起工作的女招待
Well, ere are the waitresses at my work,
在旧城镇里有一间小巧可爱的商店...
and this cute, little shop in Old Town...
停停停  没有什么实体店存在
Hush, hush, hush, hush, hush-- virtually non-existent.
我在考虑  我们首先为她
I'm thinking that we set her up
建立一个电子商务监控系统
with a hosted turnkey e-commerce system to start.
还要什么中介系统呢
Why not eliminate the middle man?
我们可以装一个小服务器群
We could install a small server farm
IP地址直接是她卧室!
with a static IP in her bedroom.
那她就需要一些工业制冷系统了
She'd need some kind of industrial cooling system.
当然了  不过慢着
Of course, but before we set up
我们建立市场营销基础设施之前
a marketing andistribution infrastructure,
必须先完善生产过程
we should finish optimizing the manufacturing process.
首先  现在有个严重问题
To start with, she has a terrible problem
闪粉因为受潮而凝固成块了
with moisture-induced glitter clump.
是啊  真是难伺候
Yeah, it's a bitch.
这我以前见过
Uh, I've seen this before.
在哪儿?
Where?
脱衣舞娘常遇到的问题
It's a common stripper problem.
她们一跳舞  一流汗  就凝固了嘛
They dance, they swe, they clump.
你是不是在考虑
Are you thinking about adding
加点硫酸钙进去用作干燥剂呢?
a desiccant ke calcium sulfate?
其实  我在想一个叫薇迦的脱衣舞娘
Actually, I'm thinking about this one stripper named Vega.
当然啦  可以用硫酸钙
But re, calcium sulfate could work.
让我们再想想别的
Let's think out the box for a moment.
用分子筛怎么样
How about a molecular sieve?
我厨房里有个意面筛子
I've got a spaghetti strainer in the kitchen.
我们可以从化学实验室
Hey, we could liberate some
拿些微孔活性炭出来
micro-porous charcoal from the chem lab.
很好  拉杰  你和霍华德去拿活性炭
Oh, great.Raj, why don't you and Howard go get the charcoal?
莱纳德  你去给网站做个初步设计
Leonard, why don't you start working on preliminary web site designs.
我去我们公寓里腾些地方出来
I'll make some space in our apartment
这样我们可以展开生产过程
so we can move the manufacturing process.
我的公寓哪里不好了?
Well, what's wrong with my apartment?
这里不是我的公寓
It's not my apartment.
等等  我该干什么
Wait, wait, what am I going to do?
呃  这是你的生意
Uh, hey, it's your business.
做你想做的任何事
Do whatever you want
好  真不错
Okay, cool.
我要睡一觉
I'm gonna take a nap.
我还在修改中
I'm still twinking things a little bit,
但能给你们看网站的大致样子了
but this will give you the general idea of the Web site.
你们觉得怎么样
So, what do you guys think?
呃  不管我用何种方式说出来
Uh, pretty much any way I say that
都会伤到他的感情的
is going to hurt his feelings.
有什么问题吗
Okay, what's wrong with it?
有什么问题
What's wrong with it?
不是你  我没在问你
Not you. I wasn't asking you.
佩妮
Penny?
呃  有一点点幼稚
Uh, well, it's a little juvenile.
看着像一个13岁女孩的
I mean, it kind of looks like the MySpace page
个人主页
of a 13-year-old girl.
不像啊
No, it doesn't.
拜托  约会热线都可以拿这个来吸引色狼了
Please. Dateline could use it to attract predators.
佩妮  这是你的公司
Penny, this is your enterprise,
所以最终决议权在于你
so it's ultimately your decision,
但基于他工作的质量
but based on the quality of his work,
我强烈建议开除莱纳德
I'd strongly recommend that we let Leonard go.
你想开除我?
You want to fire me?
我怎么想都没有关系 这是佩妮的决定
What I want is irrelevant. This is Penny's decision.
佩妮?
Penny?
等等  既然我做得那么糟
Excuse me, but if I did such a bad job,
那为什么已经有人下订单了
then why do we already have orders?
真的吗
We do?
看
Uh-huh. Look.
阿拉巴马亨斯维尔的菲奥娜·冯戴尔太太要两个
Mrs. Fiona Fondell from Huntsville, Alabama has ordered two.
没开玩笑吧  两个?
No kidding. Two? Uh-huh
看那些评论
Look at the comments.
谢谢  佩妮花花  这些为我遮羞再好不过了
Thank you, Penny Blossoms. These will be perfect, to cover my bald spot."
真感动
that is so sweet.
当作遮羞的用途
Camouflaging bald spots.
这能够吸引男士目光
That's primarily a male concern.
也许我们可以扩大市场
Perhaps could expand our market.
花花发卡怎么能吸引男人呢
How are flower barrettes going to appeal to men?
我们加上蓝牙!
We add Bluetooth!
太聪明了  男人喜欢蓝牙
Brilliant. Men love Bluetooth.
等等  等等
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
你想做一个装有蓝牙的发卡?
you want to make a hair barrette with Bluetooth?
佩妮  任何东西加上了蓝牙都会好很多
Penny, everything is better with Bluetooth.
噢  天啊
Holy crap.
有人刚订了一千个佩妮花花
Someone just ordered a thousand Penny Blossoms.
怎么可能
Get out!
谁会需要一千个带莱茵石的
Who needs a thousand sparkly flower barrettes
花花发卡
with rhinestones?
第五届新泽西州东卢瑟福德
"The Fifth Annual East Rutherford, New Jersey,
男同  女同  双性恋者和变性人联盟宴会
Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender Alliance Luau."
噢  又一个可以开拓的市场
Oh, another market to expand
裸体基佬
To balding gay men.
我打赌女同们喜欢蓝牙
And I'll bet lesbians love Bluetooth.
我们该开始工作了
We should get to work.
等等  为什么他要一天内加急交货
Wait, wait, why does it say "one-day rush"?
我们什么时候提供加急服务了
Since when do we offer a one-day rush?
亚马逊购书网提供加急服务的
Amazon offers one-day rush.
但他们又不需要把书黏在一起
Yeah, but they don't have to glue the books together.
我们怎么才能在一天内
How the hell are we going to make
做出一千个佩妮花花呢
a thousand Penny Blossoms in one day?
别对我吼啊
Don't yell at me.
我又不是负责生产的  我只负责网页设计
I'm not manufacturing. I'm just Web design.
好吧  我要去打电话取消订单
Okay, well, I'm gonna have to call and cancel the order.
什么
Excuse me,
这难道不正是你的目标吗
but was this not your goal?
通过企业的独特性
Financial independence
和创新性来达到经济独立的目的
through entrepreneurial brilliance and innovation?
是我的独特性和创新性  但仍是你的目标
My brilliance and innovation, of course, but still.
我只是不知道我们怎么才能完成这活
I just don't see how we can pull this off.
就是这种支吾的语气和自我怀疑
That, right there, that equivotion and self-doubt,
这可不是美国精神
that is not the American spirit.
戴维·克罗基特[拓荒时代英雄]放弃阿拉莫了吗
Did Davy Crockett quit at the Alamo?
吉姆·鲍伊[美国英雄人物]放弃了吗
Did Jim Bowie?
他们是没放弃  他们被宰了
They didn't quit.They were massacred...
被无数愤怒的墨西哥人宰了
by like a gazillion angry Mexicans.
这么说吧
Let me put it this way.
你这单的毛收入
Your gross receipts on this one order
将会超过3000美金  只要工作一晚
will be over $3,000 for one night's work.
大家开工
You guys get started.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
上网买鞋子
Going online to buy shoes!
她来了以后会来山里转转  来转转
* She'll be coming round the mountain when she comes * * When she comes
* She'll be coming round the mountain * * when she comes *
来转转
* When she comes *
她来了以后会来山里转转
* She'll be coming round the mountain *
* She'll be coming round the mountain... *
如果我想周六晚上干这个
You know, if I wand to spend my Saturday nights doing this,
我大可留在印度
I could have stayed in India.
别来你那套第三世界的假把戏
Oh, stop with the fake third world crap.
你父亲是妇产科医生
Your father's a gynecologist.
你有一大帮仆人
And you had a use full of servants.
我们才四个仆人
We only had four servants.
还有两个是小孩
And two of them were children.
干得怎么样了
How we doing?
还有128组佩妮花花要做
We have 128 assorted Penny Blossoms ready to ship.
天哪  按时做不完了
Oh, God, we're never gonna finish in time.
来转转  来转转
* When she comes * When she comes
-等下  -是谁让谢尔顿来做主的
Wait, hold.Who made Sheldon the boss anyway?
我想我听到工厂那边有牢骚
I believe I'm hearing some negativity on the factor floor.
怎么样
So
佩妮  劳动力是必须
Penny, the labor force is a living organism
被精心呵护的生命体
that must be carefully nurtured.
任何影响生产力的抱怨
Any counterproductive grumbling must be skillfully
必须用管理手段扼杀  看着
headed off by management. Observe
嘿
Hey!
少说话  多干活
Less talk, more work!
做得不错
Nicely done.
谢谢
Thank you.
听到什么工会的声音  告诉我
You hear any union talk, you let know.
某人和黛娜在厨房
* Someone's in the kitchen with Dinah... *
我知道某人在厨房
* Someone's in the kitchen I know-ow-ow-ow *
某人和黛娜在厨房
* Someone's in the kihen with Dinah... *
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
Sheldon!
因为我向矿工商店出卖了灵魂
* 'Cause I sold my soul to the company store. *
宝贝  来点咖啡吗
Honey, do you want some coffee?
不  我不喝咖啡
I don't drink coffee.
拜托  如果你不能醒着
Come on, but if you don't stay awake
我们无法按时完工的
we'll never finish in time.
抱歉  咖啡绝对不行
I'm sorry, coffee's out of the question.
当我搬到加州时
When I moved to California,
我向我妈保证我不会嗑药的
I promised my mother that I wouldn't start doing drugs.
莱纳德  帮帮忙
Leonard, help.
谢尔顿  还有380个要做
Sheldon, we still have 380 of these things to make
我绝对相信你们能完成的  晚安
I have complete faith that you will make them.Good night.
莱纳德
Leonard?!
谢尔顿  没有你的见解和领导
But, Sheldon,without your insight and leadership
整个公司都会垮掉
this entire enterprise will surely fail.
你说得太对了
You're right, of course.
给你  会有用的
Here, this will help.
很好
Very well,
但如果这让我麻醉或致幻
but if this leads to opiates or hallucinogenics,
你要给我妈有个交代
You're going to have to answer to my mother.
看看 普朗克常数
Look at Planck's Constant.
不能有一点偏差
It could not be less arbitrary.
如变了一点  我们熟知的生活就不存在了  嘭!
If it varied slightly, life as we know would not exist.Bang!
现在  再看一下整个推论过程
Now, now, let's reconsider the entire argument,
把熵反向  因果颠倒
but with entropy reversed and effect peceding cause.
这时的宇宙
So you are thinking a universe
不是从中心点膨胀
that's not expanding from the center--
是在从一个可能的空间中缩退  嘭!
no, it is retreating from a, from a possibility space. Bang!
在这个世界里  我们实际上都是
This is a space where we are all essentially Alice
镜子里的爱丽丝
through the looking glass,
站在红发女王前
standing in front of the Red Queen,
口渴了  只有饼干来解渴  嘭!
and we're being offered a cracker to quench our thirst. Bang!
当然  在另一个叫元期宇宙的空间里
Of course, in another universe, let's call it universe prime,
有另一个谢尔顿
there's another Sheldon
-我们该让他上床睡觉的  -嘭!
We should let him go to bed. Bang!
不敢相信我们做到了
I can't believe we actually did it.
一千个该死的佩妮花花
1,000 friggin' Penny Blossoms.
想让你们知道
I just want you guys to know
我特别感激你们的帮助
I am really grateful for your help.
我赚的每块钱  分你们20分
And for ever dollar I make, I'm gog to give you 20 cents.
那是你所有的利润
That's your entire profit margin.
噢  那算了
Oh.Then never mind.
我来打印邮寄标签
I'll print out the shipping label.
怎么了
What?
有封来自新泽西的东卢瑟福的
We got an e-mail from the East Rutherford, New Jersey,
男同  女同  双性恋  变性人联盟的邮件
Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender liance.
他们还要一千个佩妮花花
They want another thousand Penny Blossoms.
真的吗
Really?
一天内加急
One-day rush.
我真该把那个从网上删掉
I really need to take that off the Web site.
这样的话  我们要马上开工了
Okay, well, guess we'd better get started.
不是说真的吧
You can't be serious.
拜托
Come on.
工作间的生命体
What about the living organism of the workforce
和美国精神哪去了
and the American spirit?!
还有阿拉莫的吉米·克罗基特
And Jiminy Crockett at the Alamo?!
戴维·克罗基特
Davy Crockett.
吉米·克罗基特是只蟋蟀
Jiminy Crockett was cricket.
行了  行了  我知道  好了吧
yes, yes, I know that, okay?
我累死了  喝了有18杯咖啡了
I'm tired-- I've had like 18 cups of coffee.
关键是  我们振作起来  能做到的
The point is, if we just pull together, we can do this.
谁和我一起
Who's with me?
佩妮  也许你不相信
Penny, although you may find it hard to believe,
我们还是有自己的生活的
We do have lives.
莱纳德
Leonard?
抱歉
Sorry.
对新泽西的东卢瑟福的
My apologies to the gay community
同性恋联盟说的
of East Rutherford, New Jersey.
咖啡在哪
Where's the coffee?!
我们都撤了
We're all out.
没关系
No problem.
在这香蕉落地之前我会回来的
I'll be back before this banana hits the ground.
吔!
Yes!
抱歉  各位  但神秘激光障碍午餐真是愚蠢
Sorry, guys, but Secret Agent Laser Obstacle Lunch is just stupid.